Guide to the Leonard S. Marcus Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- September 2015 Acquisition, circa 1850-2015; circa 1975-2015; 110.08; (98 boxes)
  - Exhibitions and Museum Work, circa 1985-2013; 3; (3 boxes)
    - Other Exhibitions and Museum Work, circa 1985-2009
      - Golden Legacy: Original Art from 65 Years of Golden Books exhibition, Children's Museum of Manhattan, 2008–2009 (Box 62, Folder 1655-1656)
      - Storied City exhibition, New York Public Library, 2003 (Box 62, Folder 1657)
      - Every Picture Tells a Story Gallery, 1996 (Box 62, Folder 1658)
      - Margaret Wise Brown: The Poet Laureate of the Nursery exhibition, Boston Athenaeum, 1989–1993 (Box 62, Folder 1659-1665)
      - Harper Ursula Nordstrom exhibition, 1998 (Box 62, Folder 1666)
      - The Illustrators of Margaret Wise Brown exhibition proposal, 1990 (Box 62, Folder 1667)
  - Correspondence, circa 1979-2013; 3; (3 boxes)
    Marcus's professional and personal correspondence, including correspondence with literary agents, publishers, and children's book authors and illustrators.
    - General correspondence, 1979-1990 (Box 59, Folder 1587)
      Includes correspondence from X. J. Kennedy.
    - General correspondence, 1979-1990 (Box 59, Folder 1588-1594)
    - General correspondence, 1979-1990 (Box 59, Folder 1595)
      Includes correspondence from Edith Thacher Hurd.
    - General correspondence, 1979-1990 (Box 59, Folder 1596)
      Includes correspondence from X. J. Kennedy and Elizabeth Cleaver.
    - General correspondence, 1979-1990 (Box 59, Folder 1597)
    - General correspondence, 1986-2008 (Box 63, Folder 1671-1679)
    - General correspondence, 1986-2008 (Box 63, Folder 1680)
      Includes correspondence from Brian Selznick.
    - General correspondence, 1986-2008 (Box 63, Folder 1681-1683)
    - General correspondence, 1986-2008 (Box 63, Folder 1684)
      Contains correspondence from Brian Selznick.
    - General correspondence, 1990-2002 (Box 64, Folder 1685-1697)
    - General correspondence, 1984-2013 (Box 65, Folder 1698-1708)
    - General correspondence, 1984-2013 (Box 65, Folder 1709)
      Includes correspondence from X. J. Kennedy, Charlotte Zolotow, Iona Opie, Karla Kuskin, Ursula Nordstrom, and Garth Williams.
    - General correspondence, 1984-2013 (Box 65, Folder 1709a)
  - Publishing Promotional Materials and Printed Ephemera, circa 1850–2015; Bulk, 1975–2015; 4.66; (3 boxes)
    Publishing promotional material, primarily concerning children's and young adult literature. Includes a small quantity of realia, mostly produced as promotional materials for children's books. Includes other printed ephemera, including historic children's book and toy catalogs, art, posters, and ephemera from events such as the Newbery and Caldecott awards banquets.
    - Alice's Adventures in Wonderland playing cards, circa 1995-2015 (Box 66, Folder 1713)
    - Rosemary Wells drawings, circa 1995-2015 (Box 66, Folder 1714)
    - Halibut Jackson paper doll, circa 1995-2015 (Box 66, Folder 1715)
    - Michael L. Printz Awards program, 2006 (Box 66, Folder 1716)
    - Far Flung Adventures, circa 1995-2015 (Box 66, Folder 1717)
    - Peter Sís prints, circa 1995-2015 (Box 66, Folder 1718)
    - Eric Carle Museum of Picture Book Art events, 2002–2014 (Box 66, Folder 1719)
    - New York is Book Country, 2003 (Box 66, Folder 1720)
    - Coretta Scott King Book Award breakfast, 2002–2006 (Box 66, Folder 1721)
    - Seussentennial, 2004 (Box 66, Folder 1722)
    - Vladimir Radunsky events, 2008 (Box 66, Folder 1723)
    - James McMullan events, 1998–2012 (Box 66, Folder 1724)
    - The Art of Mitsumasa Anno, Eric Carle Museum of Picture Book Art, 2003 (Box 66, Folder 1725)
    - Susanne Susa, 1944 (Box 66, Folder 1726)
    - New York City Literary Honors, 2012 (Box 66, Folder 1727)
    - Newbery Caldecott Awards banquets, 1975–2013 (Box 66, Folder 1728)
    - Margaret A. Edwards Awards luncheon, 2005 (Box 66, Folder 1729)
    - Bruno Munari event, Bibliothèque Elsa Triolet, 2007 (Box 66, Folder 1730)
    - Viking Junior Books catalog, 1952–1953 (Box 66, Folder 1731)
    - Alice in Wonderland playbill, 1982 (Box 66, Folder 1732)
    - Endymion Spring promotional materials, 2006 (Box 66, Folder 1733)
    - The Amber Spyglass excerpt and promotional material, 2000 (Box 66, Folder 1734)
    - Japanese stamps designed by Mitsumasa Anno, circa 1995-2015 (Box 66, Folder 1735)
    - Illustrations and clippings, circa 1975-2015 (Box 66, Folder 1736)
    - Kerlan Collection, University of Minnesota, circa 1975-2015 (Box 66, Folder 1737)
    - University of Southern Mississippi medallion, 1978 (Box 66, Folder 1738)
    - Robert Lowell: Poet of Terribilità by Stanley Kunitz, 1974 (Box 66, Folder 1739)
    - Directions in Children's Literature, circa 1990-2012 (Box 66, Folder 1740)
    - Brian Selznick events, 2007–2015 (Box 66, Folder 1741)
    - Alice's Adventures in Wonderland pop-up by Robert Sabuda, 2003 (Box 66, Folder 1742)
    - Tom Feelings, The Middle Passage, circa 2000 (Box 66, Folder 1743)
    - Richard Jackson book launch, 2000 (Box 66, Folder 1744)
    - Brundibar by Maurice Sendak and Tony Kushner, 2004 (Box 66, Folder 1745)
    - Maurice Sendak events, 1988–2012 (Box 66, Folder 1746)
    - The New Yorker Maurice Sendak cover, 1993 (Box 66, Folder 1747)
    - Irma S. and James H. Black Award, 2007 (Box 66, Folder 1748)
    - Eloise pink and black ball, circa 1999 (Box 66, Folder 1749)
    - Carolyn Haywood Little Eddie reading, circa 1990-2015 (Box 66, Folder 1750)
    - Maurice Sendak photograph, circa 1990-2012 (Box 66, Folder 1751)
    - Viking Children's Books 75th anniversary, 2000 (Box 66, Folder 1752)
    - The Busy World of Richard Scarry, circa 1994-1997 (Box 66, Folder 1753)
    - Children's Literature Association, 2010 (Box 66, Folder 1754)
    - The Baby-Sitters Club promotional material, circa 1986-2000 (Box 66, Folder 1755)
    - One Hundred Books Famous in Children's Literature exhibition promotional material, Grolier Club, 2015 (Box 66, Folder 1756)
    - Bravo! Chris Raschka exhibition, 2009 (Box 66, Folder 1757)
    - Mazza Museum events, 2011 (Box 66, Folder 1758)
    - The Snowy Day and the Art of Ezra Jack Keats exhibition, The Jewish Museum, 2011 (Box 66, Folder 1759)
    - McLoughlin Brothers, "New Picture Books for Little Children" catalog, circa 1850-1920 (Box 66, Folder 1760)
    - The Polar Express temporary tattoo and sticker, 1985 (Box 66, Folder 1761)
    - Harry Potter flipbooks, circa 2004 (Box 66, Folder 1762)
    - Here with Me Benrei Huang exhibition, 2009 (Box 66, Folder 1763)
    - The Very Hungry Caterpillar felt toy, circa 1990-2015 (Box 66, Folder 1764)
    - Center for Teaching through Children's Books, circa 1990-2015 (Box 66, Folder 1765)
    - Dear Genius postcards, 2000 (Box 66, Folder 1766)
    - Lois Lensky exhibition, Rutgers University, 2009 (Box 66, Folder 1767)
    - McLoughlin Brothers exhibition, Brooklyn Historical Society, 2007–2009 (Box 66, Folder 1768)
    - Seeing Redd playing cards, 2007 (Box 66, Folder 1769)
    - National Association of Booksellers for Children, circa 1990-2015 (Box 66, Folder 1770)
    - Where the Wild Things Are film promotional materials, 2009 (Box 66, Folder 1771)
    - The Center for Children's Literature, circa 1990-2015 (Box 66, Folder 1772)
    - Night Kitchen Radio Theater events, circa 2006 (Box 66, Folder 1773)
    - Margaret Wise Brown, The Little Fisherman event, circa 1990-2015 (Box 66, Folder 1774)
    - Reading Rainbow contest certificate, 2000 (Box 66, Folder 1775)
    - Children's Book Council annual report, 2004 (Box 66, Folder 1776)
    - Thomas and Friends tour, 2005 (Box 66, Folder 1777)
    - Margaret Gabel event, New School writing program, 2003 (Box 67, Folder 1778)
    - Olivia Forms a Band promotional materials, 2006 (Box 67, Folder 1779)
    - Hardie Gramatky event, Westport Public Library, 2005 (Box 67, Folder 1780)
    - Jon Scieszka, circa 1995-2015 (Box 67, Folder 1781)
    - Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library party, 2006 (Box 67, Folder 1782)
    - Poetry Foundation events, 2006 (Box 67, Folder 1783)
    - Greta Schreyer and Tibor Gergely exhibit, Studio West, 2007 (Box 67, Folder 1784)
    - Girls in Pants charm, 2002 (Box 67, Folder 1785)
    - Jerry Pinkney exhibit, Brandywine River Museum, 2008 (Box 67, Folder 1786)
    - Schwartz & Wade Books, circa 1995-2015 (Box 67, Folder 1787)
    - Betsy Beinecke Shirley Collection of American Children's Literaure lecture postcards, 2006 (Box 67, Folder 1788)
    - Reading Is Fundamental 40th anniversary postcards, 2006 (Box 67, Folder 1789)
    - Richard Yarde event, 2007 (Box 67, Folder 1790)
    - Peter Sís, Mary Ryan Gallery postcard, 2008 (Box 67, Folder 1791)
    - Great Joy promotional material, 2007 (Box 67, Folder 1792)
    - Ashley Bryan exhibition postcard, National Center for Children's Illustrated Literature, 2009 (Box 67, Folder 1793)
    - Picture Play exhibition postcard, Rutgers University, 2008 (Box 67, Folder 1794)
    - X. J. Kennedy event, New York Public Library, 1990 (Box 67, Folder 1795)
    - The Big Book for Peace event, 1990 (Box 67, Folder 1796)
    - Simms Taback promotional material, circa 1995-2011 (Box 67, Folder 1797)
    - William Pène Du Bois retrospective, Schiller-Wapner Galleries, 1983 (Box 67, Folder 1798)
    - The Buck Stops Here: The Presidents of the United States exhibition press release, Henry Feiwel Gallery, 1990 (Box 67, Folder 1799)
    - Scholastic literary luncheon invitation, 2001 (Box 67, Folder 1800)
    - Here Comes Mother Goose by Iona Opie and Rosemary Wells party invitation, 1999 (Box 67, Folder 1801)
    - Children's Playmate Magazine, 1937 (Box 67, Folder 1802)
    - George McHugh Nicholson memorial, 2015 (Box 67, Folder 1803)
    - Tail Feathers from Mother Goose: The Opie Rhyme Book, circa 1988 (Box 67, Folder 1804)
    - James Marshall events, 1991–1993 (Box 67, Folder 1805)
    - The Tanager, Grinnell College, 1945 (Box 67, Folder 1806)
    - The Alchemyst by Michael Scott promotional material, 2007 (Box 67, Folder 1807)
    - Altman Books catalog, circa 1910-1920 (Box 67, Folder 1808)
    - Wanamaker's toy catalog, 1959 (Box 67, Folder 1809)
    - New York Public Library children's books suggested as holiday gifts, 1941–1949 (Box 67, Folder 1810)
    - The Boston Public Library Quarterly, 1954 (Box 67, Folder 1811)
    - HarperCollins Eric Carle exhibition invitation, 1997 (Box 67, Folder 1812)
    - Mo Willems sketchbooks, 2008–2015 (Box 67, Folder 1813)
    - Eric Carle signed prints, 2009–2014 (Box 67, Folder 1814)
    - Little Jack Frost by Charles Sangster and Tony DiTerlizzi promotional material, circa 1995-2015 (Box 67, Folder 1815)
    - Association for Library Service to Children preconference, 2013 (Box 67, Folder 1816)
    - The Horn Book Magazine, 1985 (Box 67, Folder 1817)
    - Chicago Tribune children's book advertisement, 1946 (Box 67, Folder 1818)
    - "Vanka" by Anton Chekhov, 1938 (Box 67, Folder 1819)
    - Consulting Engineer guide for authors, circa 1975-1995 (Box 67, Folder 1820)
    - "Seven Stories High" by Anne Carroll Moore, circa 1950-1960 (Box 67, Folder 1821)
    - Clippings and business cards, circa 1975-2015 (Box 67, Folder 1822)
    - Buttons, circa 1975-2015 (Box 67, Folder 1823)
    - Amber Was Brave, Essie Was Smart signed poster, 2001 (Box 94 (Oversize), Folder 2309)
    - Posters, circa 1990-2015 (Box 102, Folder 2473-2494)
  - Electronic Media, circa 1995-2014; 1.5; (2 boxes)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    Includes recordings and notes from Marcus's interviews with prominent children's literature authors, illustrators, and publishers. Also includes separated digital materials from elsewhere in the collection. Separation sheets for separated electronic media are included in their original locations in the collection.
    - 2016.genm.0036.0002: Eric Carle in Word and Interview with Eric Carle, undated; 2 (Box 69, Folder 1835)
    - 2016.genm.0036.0003: KMA Children Should be Seen, undated; 1 (Box 69, Folder 1836)
    - 2016.genm.0036.0004: Feiffer Ex. Images, 2010-07-13; 1 (Box 69, Folder 1837)
    - 2016.genm.0036.0005: Golden Books Opening ECMPBA [Eric Carle Museum of Picture Book Art], undated; 1 (Box 69, Folder 1838)
    - 2016.genm.0036.0006: CSBS, 2008-05-05; 1 (Box 69, Folder 1839)
    - 2016.genm.0036.0007: Paper Clips movie DVD, undated; 1 (Box 69, Folder 1840)
    - 2016.genm.0036.0008: Images for PowerPoint, undated; 5 (Box 69, Folder 1841)
    - 2016.genm.0036.0009: Gismos & Gadgets: Walter Wick, undated; 1 (Box 69, Folder 1842)
    - 2016.genm.0036.0010: NY Times 2003 Christmas Bks, 1 (Box 69, Folder 1843)
    - 2016.genm.0036.0012: Goodnight Moon: The exact words by Margaret Wise Brown Song created and sung by Suzanne Scheniman, 2001; 1 (Box 69, Folder 1844)
    - 2016.genm.0036.0013: UN [Ursula Nordstrom] letters copy B, undated; 1 (Box 69, Folder 1845)
    - 2016.genm.0036.0014: 2013 Acceptance Speeches [Newbery Medal, Caldecott Medal, and Laura Ingalls Wilder Award], 1 (Box 69, Folder 1846)
    - 2016.genm.0036.0015: Directions in Children's Literature #11, Sendak, undated; 1 (Box 69, Folder 1847)
    - 2016.genm.0036.0017: Curious George at 60 Garth Williams Don Freeman Paul Galdone, undated; 1 (Box 69, Folder 1848)
    - 2016.genm.0036.0018: BNF [Bibliothèque nationale de France] PowerPoint - Maurice Sendak talk, 2013-12-12; 1 (Box 69, Folder 1849)
    - 2016.genm.0036.0019: Margaret Wise Brown "Eveillée [par] la Lune" Leonard S. Marcus, undated; 1 (Box 69, Folder 1850)
    - 2016.genm.0036.0020: Hurd Photos, undated; 1 (Box 69, Folder 1851)
    - 2016.genm.0036.0021: Music from Our Lord's Holy Heaven, Gathered and Sung by Gloria Jean Pinkney, 2004; 2 (Box 69, Folder 1852)
    - 2016.genm.0036.0022: Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 69, Folder 1853)
    - 2016.genm.0036.0023: lengle.tif de Grummond Children's Literature Collection USA, 2003; 1 (Box 69, Folder 1854)
      Manuscript page 130 from A Wrinkle in Time by Madeleine L'Engle, de Grummond Children's Literature Collection, McCain Library and Archives, The University of Southern Mississippi.
    - 2016.genm.0036.0024: Diana Wynne Jones photos, undated; 1 (Box 69, Folder 1855)
    - 2016.genm.0036.0025: Morrow Junior Books History (Fall 1995), 1 (Box 69, Folder 1856)
    - 2016.genm.0036.0026: The Borrowers Revised, undated; 1 (Box 69, Folder 1857)
    - 2016.gem.0036.0027: Medal Man: Randolph Caldecott and the Art of the Picture Book, undated; 1 (Box 69, Folder 1858)
    - 2016.genm.0036.0029: No Such Animal Chas [Charles] Green Shaw, undated; 1 (Box 69, Folder 1859)
    - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2204)
    - Christine Jenkins, 2011-06-07; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2205)
    - James VanOosting and Frederica Brenneman, 2011-12-27; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2206)
    - Henry Rinehart, 2011-04-28; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2207)
    - Judy Blume, 2011-07-12; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2208)
    - Barbara Braver, 2011-09-26; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2209)
    - Tom Barron on Madeleine L'Engle, 2010-11-12; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2210)
    - Thomas Banchoff, 2011-06-24; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2211)
    - Sister Avent, 2011-05-02; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2212)
    - Dana Catharine on Madeleine L'Engle, 2009-10-16; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2213)
    - Dana Catharine, 2011-12-21; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2214)
    - Susan Buckley on Madeleine L'Engle, 2010-10-20; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2215)
    - Nancy Bruce/Madeleine L'Engle, undated; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2216)
    - Elsa Rael Recording + TR, 2011-07-01; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2217)
    - Neal Porter on Madeleine L'Engle, 2010-07-15; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2218)
    - Sidney Offit on Madeleine L'Engle, 2010-10-14; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2219)
    - George McHorson on Madeleine L'Engle, 2010-10-12; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2220)
    - Dana Catharine, 2011-12-21; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2221)
    - Gretchen Gubelman, 2011-08-25; 2 (Box 91, Folder 2222-2223)
    - Carmen Gomez-Plata, 2010-12-08; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2224)
    - Peter Glassman, 2011-03-11; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2225)
    - Charlotte Hand, 2011-07-05; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2226)
    - James Parks Morton, 2009-06-25; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2227)
    - Paul Moravec on Madeleine L'Engle, 2011-03-07; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2228)
    - Gardner McFall, 2011-03-30; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2229)
    - Betsy Hearne, 2011-06-09; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2230-2231)
    - Trish Marx, 2011-05-19; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2232)
    - Beverly Horowitz on Madeleine L'Engle, 2010-09-20; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2233)
    - Christine Jenkins, 2011-06-07; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2234)
    - Marcie Imberman, 2011-05-23; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2235)
    - Interview with William Alexander Johnson about Madeleine L'Engle taped at the Lotus Club, NYC, 2009-05-28; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2236)
    - Christine Jenkins, 2011-06-07; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2237)
    - Alan Jones, 2011-06-27; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2238)
    - Robert Lescher, 2011-04-28; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2239)
    - Charlotte Jones, 2011-06-21; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2240)
    - Bridget Marmion, 2011-03-11; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2241)
    - Don Lundquisr - TR - Unedited Alan Jones - TR - Edited, 2011-06-27-2011-06-29; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2242)
    - Don Lundquist, 2011-06-29; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2243)
    - Helen Lentz on Madeleine L'Engle, 2010-10-21; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2244)
    - Wendy Lamb on Madeleine L'Engle, 2011-02-24; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2245)
    - Amy Kellman, 2011-05-05; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2246)
    - Sandra Jordan on Madeleine L'Engle, 2010-08-25; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2247)
    - Gay Jordan (Elwell), 2011-03-24; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2248)
    - Josephine Jones, 2011-07-08; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2249)
    - Charlotte Voiklis TR, 2011-06-23; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2250)
    - Steig II (Carle Museum), 2010-07-10; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2251)
    - Jason Epstein, ( Annotated Phantom Tollbooth ); Jean Feiwel ( Horn Book ), 2008-12-16-2009-05-19; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2252)
    - Madeleine L'Engle interview transcripts William Alexander Johnson Luci Shaw, 2009-05-28-2009-08-14; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2253)
    - Peter Sís, 2009-07-23; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2254)
    - Chris Raschka, 2009-07-24; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2255)
    - Yumi Heo interview, 2009-09-18; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2256)
    - Vera B. Williams, 2009-11-09; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2257)
    - Mo Willems, 2009-12-02; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2258)
    - Maurice Sendak, 2011-05-12; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2259)
    - Winding Oak Files, undated; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2260)
    - AAA Shaw Essay, Annotated Phantom Tollbooth folder, Annotated Phantom Tollbooth 2, Luci Shaw transcript, Masterpieces folder, M. Engelbreit 3 folder, New Speaking folder, Treasure Bks (Hartford) File, NY Times, undated; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2261)
    - Sheldon Fogelman, 2010-09-14; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2262)
    - Interview on Leonard Lopate Show, 2008-07-01; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2263)
    - Transcripts: Christine Jenkins, Trish Marx, Marcie Imberman, Mary Pope Osborne, undated; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2264)
    - Deborah Sloan, 2014-02-07; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2265)
    - David Ford, 2014-01-10; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2266)
    - Transcripts Gregory Maguire (edited) Thomas Banchoff (edited) Charlotte Voiklis (raw), undated; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2267)
    - Gregory McGuire [Maguire], 2011-06-23; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2268)
    - Jules Feiffer, 2011-06-28; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2269)
    - Barbara Scotto, 2011-08-17; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2270)
    - Photos of me by Elene Seibert + Sonya Sones, 2011; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2271)
    - Nancy Drew, 2011-08-13; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2272)
    - Cynthia Zarin, 2011-07-01; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2273)
    - Jane Yolen, 2011-05-21; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2274)
    - Katherine Weber, 2011-05-18; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2275)
    - James VanOosting Frederica Brenneman, 2011-12-27; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2276)
    - Jerry Pinkney, 2011-06-20; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2277)
    - Colby Rodowsky, 2011-06-27; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2278)
    - Stephen Roxburgh, 2011-07-15; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2279)
    - Ginger Shuler on Maurice Sendak, 2012-10-15; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2280)
    - Brian Selznick, 2013-04-11; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2281)
    - My photos of Caldecott sites, 2012-03; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2282)
    - Bernard Waber, 2012-11-13; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2283)
    - Bernard Waber, 2012-12-20; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2284)
    - Mira Rothenberg, 2011-08-11; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2285)
    - Patrick Rodgers, 2013-03-14; 2 (Box 91, Folder 2286-2287)
    - Geoffrey Hayes, 2013-11-04; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2288)
    - Hope Larson, 2013-11-15; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2289)
    - Harry Bliss, 2013-12-02; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2290)
    - Sara Varon, 2013-11-11; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2291)
    - Amelia Edwards + Joanna Carey, 2013-11-22; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2292)
    - All 3 Helen Oxenbury Interviews London/Felixstowe, 2013-11; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2293)
    - Helen Oxenbury, 2013-11-21; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2294)
    - James Sturm, 2013-12-17; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2295)
    - Dave Roman, 2013-12-09; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2296)
    - Gene Luen Yang, 2014-01-03; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2297)
    - Helen Oxenbury book: David Lloyd Helen Oxenbury (2/28/14) Neal Porter Liz Attenborough, circa 2014; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2298)
    - John Burningham and Helen Oxenbury, 2010-09-29; 1 (Box 91, Folder 2299)
  - Sound Recordings, circa 1981-2009; 22.08; (21 boxes)
    Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    Includes recordings from Marcus's interviews with prominent children's literature authors, illustrators, and publishers. Also includes separated audiovisual materials from elsewhere in the collection. Separation sheets for separated sound recordings are included in their original locations in the collection.
    - 2016.genm.0036.0001: Eric Carle Interview, undated; 2 (Box 70, Folder 1860)
    - 2016.genm.0036.0011: Goodnight Moon - Demo Song, Suzanne Scheniman, 2001-08-22; 1 (Box 70, Folder 1861)
    - 2016.genm.0036.0016: Carolyn Haywood Reads, undated; 1 (Box 70, Folder 1862)
    - 2016.genm.0036.0028: Sandra Summer tells and sings Noon Balloon...and other stories by Margaret Wise Brown, the author of Good Night Moon, 1995; 1 (Box 70, Folder 1863)
    - Allen Say, 1989-08-31; 2 (Box 70, Folder 1864-1865)
    - Leonard S. Marcus on Goodnight Moon on "Poetry-in-the-Morning," WNYE-FM, 1997-03-27; 2 (Box 70, Folder 1866-1867)
    - Anne Schwartz, 1995-04-28; 1 (Box 70, Folder 1868)
    - Phyllis Fogelman, 1998-07-10; 2 (Box 70, Folder 1869-1870)
    - Mitsumasa Anno, 1989-04-22; 2 (Box 70, Folder 1871-1872)
    - Grace Mayer on René d'Harnoncourt, undated; 1 (Box 70, Folder 1873)
    - Jean George interview, undated; 2 (Box 70, Folder 1874-1875)
    - Gary Paulsen, 1997-11-26; 1 (Box 70, Folder 1876)
    - Lois Lowry, 1998-06-11; 1 (Box 71, Folder 1877)
    - Interview with Bruce Brooks, Silver Spring, Maryland, 1990-05-29; 1 (Box 71, Folder 1878)
    - James Howe, 1997-12-24; 1 (Box 71, Folder 1879)
    - Maine Lobsterman, undated; 1 (Box 71, Folder 1880)
    - Jeffrey [Potter?] - MWB [Margaret Wise Brown] tape #1 - Little Cowboy, Runaway Bunny Songs - MWB's voice, undated; 1 (Box 71, Folder 1881)
    - Larry Hughes (Wm Morrow), 1995-05-25; 1 (Box 71, Folder 1882)
    - Johanna Hurwitz, 1997-05-02; 1 (Box 71, Folder 1883)
    - Catherine Woolley (Morrow history), 1995; 1 (Box 71, Folder 1884)
    - Larry Kettelkamp, 1995-04-18; 1 (Box 71, Folder 1885)
    - ABA 1988 M. Sendak & Judy Blume, 1 (Box 71, Folder 1886)
    - Mary Calhoun, 1995-04-28; 1 (Box 71, Folder 1887)
    - David Reuther, 1995-09-07; 1 (Box 71, Folder 1888)
    - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 71, Folder 1889)
      Removed from a box labeled "Artist/Author Interviews; Small Press."
    - KW [Katharine Weber] + Madeleine L'Engle, Goshen, CT, 1988-07-11; 1 (Box 71, Folder 1890)
    - Interview with Norton Juster, 2006-06-20; 1 (Box 72, Folder 1891)
    - Norton Juster, 2007-01-17; 1 (Box 72, Folder 1892)